

COMM 2312 Technical and Professional Communication Dr. Jörg Muth Fall 2019 Class section 107

Assignment 1: Resume and Cover Letter for a Job Application

Written by Abdulrahman Emad S Aleid PMU# 201800290

Abdulrahman Emad S Aleid 22nd St., 4789 31952 Alkhobar +966 55 637 7456 aleid.2009@gamil.com

Cashier Department
Tamimi Market
Prince Hamoud St., s103
Alkhobar
Entry level Cashier | Full time

Dear Ladies and Gentlemen,

Professionalism is a continuous quest.

Having said belief in the back of my mind, motivated me to know more about how the business is run at the Canadian grocery store Urban Fare. As a result, I reached a higher level of perfecting the job. In addition, I developed people skills by properly understanding each situation and reacting accordingly. Effortlessly, I was able to handle the pressure of rush hours. Meeting customers need is first priority. By following rules and regulations, I found solutions.

Adaptability is my strongest skill; living abroad for about five years opened my perception to numerus cultures and ethnicities, which allowed me to interact and adjust with ease. Furthermore, working in a team and eventually training new team members strengthened my leadership and team work skills. Challenges to me are opportunities for further development.

Working hard at school and aiming for the highest results possible, with GPA 3.95, proves my seriousness when it comes to my interests. The responsibility characteristics I have are shown by being the vice president of the Techno Hub Club at Prince Mohammed bin Fahad University. The values and principles of your company are respectfully admired.

I am looking forward to having a job interview.

Sincerely,

Abdulrahman Emad S Aleid

Abdulrahman Emad S Aleid

Resume

22nd Street, 776 &

20775 Alkhobar

Saudi Arabia 🌐

+966 55 637 7456 🖠

aleid.2009@gmail.com ⊠

Education

2018-2019, Prince Mohammad bin Fahad University

Information Technology, 35 Credit Hours, GPA 3.95.

2014-2016, Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, Canada

Electrical Engineering, not graduated.

2012-2014, VGC International College, Vancouver, Canada

School of English Language.

2006-2009, High School Degree

General Accumulative Average 98.77.

Work Experience

Summer 2018 And Summer 2019, Family Business (Flower Shop)

Managing daily financials. Suggesting creative designs. Directing and informing customers. Keeping the store organized throughout the day.

2016-2018, Urban Fare Grocery Store (Meat Department), Vancouver, Canada

Attending customers and communicating with them. Flawless multitasking between setting up the department, keeping up with demands, and preparing customers' orders. Professionally working in a team of five. Covering all shifts from opening to closing. Training new employees.

Volunteer Work

2003-2006, Every Ramadan, Preparing Meals for the Less Fortunate People at A Local Mosque Adapting to fast base, high pressure job. Organizing people. Distributing meals. Keeping friendly welcoming attitude. Cleaning everything and keeping the place tidy.

Additional Skills

- Microsoft Office proficiency.
- Intermediate Software Programming; in Java, Hyper Text Mark-up Language, Cascading Style Sheets.

Language Skills

Arabic, native.

English, very good.

Hobbies

- · Graphic Design; in Figma.
- · Drawing.



Cashier

Job Description:

Cashier / The cashier should be familiar with all the principles and procedures required to provide services to customers, including meeting customer needs and paying attention to quality standards of services, evaluating customer satisfaction and responsible for determining product prices, scheduling invoices and completing cash transactions.

Minimum Requirements:

- Knowledge of English and Arabic language will be an added plus.
- Should have the knowledge to operate the check stand.
- High School diploma.

Preferred Skills:

Knowledge of arithmetic and simple applications.

Employee Benefits:

- Medical Insurance as per company policy
- Full month vacation pay after completion of 12 months in service
- Transportation Allowance
- Food Allowance
- Housing Allowance